# **Antoine Soetewey**

antoinesoetewey.com · antoine.soetewey@uclouvain.be

# Summary

I am a PhD candidate in statistics at UCLouvain in Belgium, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on bio-statistical methods applied to cancer patients.

In parallel with my doctoral thesis, I am teaching assistant for several courses in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level. I also provide trainings and consulting in data science, statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service.

In my spare time, I write about statistics and code in R via my blog statsandr.com.

### Education

	Education
2017 – Present	<ul> <li>PhD in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium</li> <li>Thesis: Life and health actuarial pricing: a biostatistics approach (supervisors: Prof. Catherine Legrand and Prof. Michel Denuit)</li> <li>All publications, posters and talks available at antoinesoetewey.com/research</li> </ul>
2015 – 2016	<b>MSc in econometrics &amp; operations research</b> – Maastricht University, Netherlands - Thesis: <i>Combining professional and survey forecasts for macroeconomic data</i> (supervisor: Prof. Nalan Basturk)
2013 – 2015	<ul> <li>MSc in economics – KULeuven, Belgium</li> <li>Thesis: Negativity bias and framing effect in charity donations: a field experiment (supervisor: Prof. Jo Swinnen)</li> <li>Faculty exchange of one semester at University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA</li> </ul>
2010 – 2013	BSc in economics & management sciences – UCLouvain, Belgium  Tooching experience
	Teaching experience
2024	<b>Visiting lecturer</b> for the course "Advanced quantitative methods" – UNamur, Belgium
2017 – Present	<b>Teaching assistant</b> in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium - See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching
2018 – Present	Instructor for UCLouvain's university certificates in statistics – SMCS, Belgium

## Industry experience

#### 2018 - Present

Consultant in statistics and data analysis for:

- Researchers and academics SMCS, Belgium
- Professionals and companies datanalyze.be

#### 2016 - 2017

Data scientist - Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization

# Technical skills & languages

## Software

- R (RStudio, R Markdown & Quarto, R Shiny), Jamovi, GitHub/GitLab, LATEX
- Web development
- See examples of projects at antoinesoetewey.com/software

## Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (basic)